All India Trade Union Congress Archives
International Institute of Social History
- Working Committee (AITUC), 1958-60
  - WC Meetings of AITUC
    Draft resolution and press clippings on central government employers strike adopted by AITUC; Ecerpts of speeches by TU leaders; Industry wise membership of different central trade unions, Report on the relief fund collection; Papers related to the AITUC working committee meeting; Note on tatanagar foundry closer, report, resolutions and agenda of the AITUC working committee meetings. Attendece list of the working committee meeting.
    - 106, Relief Fund, 1960; 4.35.1
    - Draft Resolution, On Central Govt. Employees Strike, 1960; 4.35.2
    - Points from Speeches- Discussion on Report, 1960; 4.35.3
    - Monthly Report from State, 1960; 4.35.4
    - Report on the Relief Fund Collections, 1960; 4.35.5
    - Resolutions to be Drafted, WC File, 1960; 4.35.6
    - On Central Govt. Employees Strike of July 1960, 4.35.7
    - 13-8-60 WC Meeting-Delhi- Sep 11&12,1960, 4.35.8
    - Agenda, 1960; 4.35.9
    - Resolutions to be Drafted, Paper Clippings, 1960; 4.35.10
    - On Mass Dismissals in Bengal Enamel Works, 1960; 4.35.11
    - On Tatanagar Foundry Closure, 1960; 4.35.12
    - On Repnession in Coal Industry, 1960; 4.35.13
    - On Anane, 1960; 4.35.14
    - 13-9-60 Resolutions on Wage Boards for Plantation, 1960; 4.35.15
    - On Dranghi in Andhra Pradesh & Mysore State, 1960; 4.35.16
    - On President Wilhelm Pieck, 1960; 4.35.17
    - On Com. Sisir Roy, 1960; 4.35.18
    - 2nd Plan, 1960; 4.35.19
    - Documents AITUC WC Meeting-Delhi-Sep 11-12,1960, 4.35.20
    - Resolutions to be drafted, AITUC WC Meeting-Delhi-Sep 11-12,1960, 4.35.21
  - Working Committee (AITUC)
    Correspondence between AITUC general Secretary K.G. Shrivastava and Petroleum workmen's union, S.A. Dange, A.K. Gopalan and India coffee board workers' co-operative society.
    - 23-1-60 Letters on Postcards, 1960; 4.33.1
      English; Warangal, Calcutta, Indore
    - 6-9-60 Dear Com. Srivastava, 1960; 4.33.2
    - 2-8-60 My Dear Com. Srivastava, 1960; 4.33.3
      English; Baripanda
    - 18-2-60 Dear Sir, The Secretary, 1960; 4.33.4
    - 17-2-60 Dear Comrade, Secretary, 1960; 4.33.5
    - 9-2-60 Telegram, Nagpur, 1960; 4.33.6
    - 11-2-60 Telegram, Bombay Dadar, 1960; 4.33.7
    - 9-2-60 Alleppey, 1960; 4.33.8
    - 9-2-60 Dear Comrade Dange, 1960; 4.33.9
    - 8-2-60 Dear Comrade, Com. SA Dange, 1960; 4.33.10
    - 6-2-60 Dr. P.M. Pillai, 1960; 4.33.11
    - 27-1-60 Dear Comrade, Com. Narasimha Rao, 1960; 4.33.12
      English; Warangal
    - 27-1-60 Dear Com. Kapatia, 1960; 4.33.13
    - 23-1-60 Dear Comrade, A.K. Gopalan, 1960; 4.33.14
      English; Cannanore
    - 20-1-60 Dear Comrade, SS Mirajkar, 1960; 4.33.15
    - 14-1-60 The Delhi Maharashtriya Samaj Building Trust, 1960; 4.33.16
    - 14-1-60 Dear Sir, The Manager, 1960; 4.33.17
    - 14-1-60 Dear Sir, The Secretary, 1960; 4.33.18
    - 12-1-60 Dear Sir, The Secretary, 1960; 4.33.19
- Secretariat of AITUC, 1957-61
  - Speech (Dange's)
    The collection contains speeches and writings of S.A. Dange, Indrajit Gupta, Bhpesh Gupta and other trade unionist of AITUC on workers' issues, Industrial employment amendment bill, companies amendment bill general budget, tripartite meeting, five years' plan and economic growth. Notes on the 3rd National Conference for Afro-Asian solidarity, speeches by foreign degniteries and a note on economic cooperation between India and Yugoslavia by Yugoslavian Embassy. Report on the 17th session of ECAF statement by K.B. Panikker and a press note on the demonstration in Delhi following the Murder of Patrice Lumumba.
    - Perspectives of a New World and the Task of the working class, 1960; 5.107.1
    - Dange on General Budget, 1960; 5.107.2
    - Sweep of Freedom, 1960; 5.107.3
    - Indrajit Gupta on Industrial employment(Standing orders) Amendment Bill, 1960; 5.107.4
    - Economic Cooperation with India, 1960; 5.107.5
    - 26th Session of the AITUC, 1961; 5.107.6
    - Salute to Coimbatore, 1961; 5.107.7
    - A Decade of Planned Economy, 1961; 5.107.8
      English; Mysore
    - Special Correspondent Dispatch, 1961; 5.107.9
    - Ecafe Seventeenth Session, 1961; 5.107.10
    - Political Prerequisites for rapid economic growth, 1961; 5.107.11
      Typed
    - A.K..Gopalan's Presidential Speech in Kisan Sabha Session, 1961; 5.107.12
  - Party (AITUC)
    The collection contains resolutions passed at the 9th conference of the West Bengal Unit of the CPI. Documents related to the Party headquarter branch of CPI, their draft political resolution on international situation and partys' task along with a note on the central party daily newspaper. Letter dealing with the west-German assistance in the Rourkela plant.
    - Resolution on PE/ CE Movement, 1961; 5.86.1
    - Conference of the General office party, 1961; 5.86.2
    - GB Meetings, 1961; 5.86.3
    - Letter from K.G.Srivastava, 1961; 5.86.4
    - PHQ General Body Meeting, 1961; 5.86.5
    - Note on The Central Party Daily, 1961; 5.86.6
    - Dear Com. P.C. Joshi, 1961; 5.86.7
      English; Rourkela
    - Dear Comrade Srivastava & Company, 1961; 5.86.8
  - Coal, Non - Coal
    Correspondence and doccuments related to the worker's issues and union's demands in Mica, Coal, Bauxite, Gold, Iron Ore, Lignite, Magnesite, Manganese mines; Papers related to the mining unions from different states like Andhra Pradesh, Bihar, Madhya Pradesh, West Bengal, Keonjhar, Mysore, Singareni like, Madhya Pradesh Sanyukta Khadan Mazdoor Sangh, Hyderabad Gold Mines Labour Union, Singareni Collieries Workers Union etc.; Workers' strikes in the mining sector.
    - 16-12-55 Letter to The General Secretary, Mica Workers' Union, Gudur, 1955; 5.746.1
    - 14-12-55 Indian Posts and Telegraphs Department, 1955; 5.746.2
    - 18-6-55 Letter to The Labour Minister, Govt. of Bihar, 1955; 5.746.3
    - 13-6-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC Delhi, 1955; 5.746.4
      Hindi; Delhi
    - 30-5-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.5
    - 20-4-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.6
      English; Nagpur
    - 13-4-55 Letter to Com. Prem Nath Bhandari, Samyukta Khadan Mazdoor Sangh, 1955; 5.746.7
      English; Balaghat (M.P.)
    - 1-4-55 Letter from Com. Prem Nath Bhandari, In Urdu, 1955; 5.746.8
      Urdu; Balaghat (M.P.)
    - 12-4-55 Letter to The General Secretary, Samyukta Khadan Mazdoor Sangh, 1955; 5.746.9
      English; Dhanbad
    - 9-4-55 Gazette No. 15 Order, 1955; 5.746.10
    - 26-4-55 Letter to Dear Com. Dange, 1955; 5.746.11
    - 24-4-55 Before the Central Govt. Tribunal, Dhanbad, 1955; 5.746.12
    - 16-5-53 Letter to The Office Secretary, AITUC, 1953; 5.746.13
    - 16-5-55 Letter to The Editor New Age, For Publication, 1955; 5.746.14
    - 12-5-55 Letter By M.P. Sanyukta Khadan Mazdor Sangh, In Urdu, 1955; 5.746.15
      Urdu; Nagpur
    - 1-4-55 Pamplet of M.P. Sanyukta Khadan Mazdor Sangh, 1955; 5.746.16
      Hindi; Nagpur
    - 5-8-55 Letter from Com. Prem Nath Bhandari, In Urdu, 1955; 5.746.17
    - 19-7-55 Pamlets-Mazdoor Ekta Jindabaad, 1955; 5.746.18
    - 18-6-55 Lettrer, M.P. Sanyuktha Khadan Mazdor Sangh-In Urdu, 1955; 5.746.19
    - 16-6-55 Pamplets of M.P. Sanyuktha Khadan Mazdor Sangh, Varshik Adhiveshan, 1955; 5.746.20
    - 5-8-55 Main Points in the letter from Com.Prem Nath Bhandari, 1955; 5.746.21
    - 1-9-55 Letter to Com. Jen, Secrt. AITUC, 5.746.22
    - Letter to Com. S.A.Dange, General Secrt. AITUC, 1955; 5.746.23
      English / Hindi; Balaghat (M.P.)
    - 8-8-55 Report from Krishna Modi, 1955; 5.746.24
      English; Katangmari
    - 4-4-55 Letter to Shri Com. General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.25
      Hindi; M.P.
    - 5-9-55 Letter to Com. MahindraSen, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.26
    - 1-9-55 Translation of main points in the letter in Urdu from Com.Prem Chand Bahandari, 5.746.27
    - 29-10-55 Letter to Com.Prem Chand Bahandari, 1955; 5.746.28
    - 12-10-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.29
    - 14-10-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.30
      Urdu
    - 15-11-55 Copy Translation, M.P.Samyukta Mine Workers' Fedration, 1955; 5.746.31
    - 15-11-55 Letter to Mr. Tanulal Mandalwar, Orissa, 1955; 5.746.32
      Hindi; Orissa
    - 16-12-54 Letter to Com. Dange,In Urdu and English, 1955; 5.746.33
      Urdu / English
    - 28-11-55 Letter from Com. Prem Nath Bhandari, 1955; 5.746.34
    - 28-11-55 Letter to Com. Dange, 1955; 5.746.35
    - 3-11-55 Letter To Com. Krishna Modi, Joint Secret. M.P. Sanyuktha Khadan Mazdor Sangh, 1955; 5.746.36
    - 18-12-55 Letter in Urdu, 1955; 5.746.37
    - 18-12-55 Letter to Com. Dange, 1955; 5.746.38
    - 5-9-55 Letter to The Secretary, Magnesite Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.39
    - 1-9-55 Letter to Dear Bala Chandran, 5.746.40
      English; Salem
    - 22-8-55 Letter to The Chief Labour Commissioner, Govt. of India, 1955; 5.746.41
    - 19-7-55 Letter to The Resional Labour Commissioner (Central), 1955; 5.746.42
      English; Suramangalam
    - 4-8-55 Letter to Shri M. Kalyasundaram, M.L.A. Madras, 1955; 5.746.43
    - 21-7-55 Letter to Thye Secretary, The Magnisite Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.44
    - 1-3-55 Letter to The Acting Manager & The President Magnesite Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.45
    - 10-6-55 Minutes of Discussions, 1955; 5.746.46
    - 13-10-55 Letter to The Secretary, Salem Magnesite Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.47
      English; Tamil Nad
    - 6-10-55 Letter to the Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.48
    - 12-9-55 Letter to Com. P.Balachandra Menon, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.49
    - 19-4-55 Letter to The General Secretary, Tamil Nad Trade Union Congress, 1955; 5.746.50
    - 20-12-54 Letter to Dear Com. Gyan Da, 1954; 5.746.51
      English; Keonjhar
    - Demand of Profit-Sharing Bons of Manganese and Iron Mining Workmen of Keonjhar-Sadhan Mukherjee, 1954; 5.746.52
      English; Orrisa
    - 4-8-55 Letter to Shri P. Mozoomdar, President, Forest & Mineral Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.53
    - 21-7-55 Letter to Shri S.A.Dange, General Secretary AITUC, 1955; 5.746.54
      English; Singhbhum
    - 14-8-55 Letter to Shri S.A.Dange, General Secretary AITUC, 1955; 5.746.55
    - 5-8-1955 Letter to Shri S.A.Dange, General Secretary AITUC, 5.746.56
    - 5-2-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.57
    - 14-4-55 Letter to The Secretary AITUC, 1955; 5.746.58
      English; Hutti, Raichur
    - 14-1-55 The Champion Reef Mine Labour Association-Card, 1955; 5.746.59
    - 18-4-55 Letter to The Reiginal Labour Commissioner, 1955; 5.746.60
    - 31-3-55 Letter to The Supretendent, The Hyderabad Gold Mines Co. Ltd., 1955; 5.746.61
    - 22-4-55 Letter to The Editor, Trade Union, 1955; 5.746.62
      English; Raichur
    - 21-4-55 Resolution Passing Note to Dear Com., 1955; 5.746.63
    - 20-2-55 Report of the Generaln Secretary, 1955; 5.746.64
    - 22-4-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.65
    - 20 20-4-55 Letter to The Supretendent, The H.G.M. Co. Ltd., 1955; 5.746.66
    - 29-10-55 letter to Com.&General Secretary, The Hyderabad Gold Mines Co. Ltd., 1955; 5.746.67
    - 20-4-55 Letter to Com. Vasan, Kolar Gold Field, 1955; 5.746.68
    - 2-4-55 Letter to Com. S.A.Dange, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.69
    - 27-4-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.70
    - 14-5-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.71
    - A Brief Report on the Strike of the 15000 Gold Mines of Kolar Gold Fieds in India, 1955; 5.746.72
    - 21-5-55 Letter to The Conciliation Officer (Central), 1955; 5.746.73
    - 2-5-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.74
    - 29-5-55 Letter to The Editor, 1955; 5.746.75
    - 7-6-55 Letter to The Secretary, AHTUC, 1955; 5.746.76
    - 7-6-55 Note on Conformation of Hunger Strike Dession of Com. P.Narayanan, General Secertary, 1955; 5.746.77
      English / Urdu / South Indian; Raichur
    - 13-6-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.78
    - For Favour of Publication, 1955; 5.746.79
    - 22-5-55 Indian Posts and Telegraphs Department, 1955; 5.746.80
    - 23-7-55 Letter to The President Com. J.B.Vittal Rao, 1955; 5.746.81
    - 23-7-1955 Letter to Com. S.A.Dange, Secretary AITUC, 5.746.82
    - 25-7-55 List of Subjects Suggested by the Labour Dept. for the forthcoming Tripartite Conference, 1955; 5.746.83
    - 26-7-55 Letter to The Disrict Collector, 1955; 5.746.84
    - 9-8-55 Letter to Dear Com. Narasimhan & Premnath, 1955; 5.746.85
    - 13-8-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.86
    - Notification No. L.S. 4218/L.W. 122-54-3, 1954; 5.746.87
    - 30-8-55 Letter to Com. P. Narayanan, Hyderabad Gold Mines Labour Union, 1955; 5.746.88
    - 23-8-55 Letter to Com. T.B.Vittal Rao, President, 1955; 5.746.89
    - 8-8-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.90
    - 29-7-55 Letter to Snri P.Narayanan, General Secretary, HGM Labour Union, 1955; 5.746.91
    - 27-9-55 Letter to Snri P.Narayanan, General Secretary, HGM Labour Union, 1955; 5.746.92
    - 20-9-55 Short Note on Hutti Gold Mines, By-P. Narayan, Secretary, 1955; 5.746.93
      English; Hutti
    - 29-7-55 Letter to Snri P.Narayanan, General Secretary, HGM Labour Union, 1955; 5.746.94
    - 14-9-55 Notice, Snri P.Narayanan, General Secretary, HGM Labour Union, 1955; 5.746.95
    - 1-10-55 Letter to Com. M.C. Narasimhana, 1955; 5.746.96
    - 12-10-55 Letter to Com. P.Balchandrra menon, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.97
    - 28-11-55 Letter to Com. T.B.Vithal Rao, M.P. & Com. Makhdoom Mohiuddin, Asstt. Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.98
    - 24-11-55 Resolution Passed in the Working Committee, 1955; 5.746.99
    - 2-12-55 Letter to the President, Mysore Principal Committee of AITUC, 1955; 5.746.100
    - Letter to Dear Comrade Dange, 1955; 5.746.101
    - 11-2-55 Letter to The AITUC Secretary, AITUC, 1953; 5.746.102
    - 18-2-55 Letter to Dear Com. Lalit, 1955; 5.746.103
    - 5-6-55 Letter to Dear Com. Dange, 1955; 5.746.104
    - 27-5-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.105
    - 20-4-55 Letter to The Regional Lanour Commissioner (Central), 1955; 5.746.106
    - 13-6-55 Letter to Dear Com. Chaturanan Misra, 1955; 5.746.107
    - 6-6-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.108
    - 6-6-55 Letter to \the Superintendent of Collieries, 1955; 5.746.109
      English; Giridih
    - 9-6-55 Letter to Dear Com. Chaturanan Misra, 1955; 5.746.110
    - 29-6-55 Letter to Dear Comrade, 1955; 5.746.111
    - 7-7-55 Letter to The Secretary, Singareni Colliery workers Union, 1955; 5.746.112
    - 29-6-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.113
      English; Kothagudium
    - 4-7-55 Letter to Com. Chaturanan Misra, Coal Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.114
    - 21-6-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.115
    - Copy of Letter No. 2663, 1955; 5.746.116
      English; Kurhurbaree
    - 29-6-55 letter to The Chief Minig Engineer, 1955; 5.746.117
    - 27-7-55 Statement on Bhowra EP Idem IC, 1955; 5.746.118
    - 20-7-55 Hindred Coal Miners Die of Cholera, 1955; 5.746.119
    - 5-7-55 Letter regarding Cheque of Dear Com. Vittal Rao, M.P., 1955; 5.746.120
    - 2-8-55 in Favour of Publication, 1955; 5.746.121
      English; E-Bengal
    - 10-7-55 Letter to Dear Com. Sanyal, 1955; 5.746.122
    - 25-7-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.123
    - Resulation, 1955; 5.746.124
    - 3-9-55 Letter to The General Secretary, Coal Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.125
    - 26-7-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.126
    - 5-9-55 Letter to Com. Chaturanan Misra, Coal Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.127
    - 31-7-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.128
    - 13-9-55 Letter to Com. Chaturanan Misra, Coal Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.129
    - 9-9-55 Letter to Com. S.A.Dange, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.130
    - 16-9-55 Letter to Com. Chaturanan Misra, Coal Workers' Union, 1955; 5.746.131
    - 10-9-55 Letter to Com. P. Balachandra Menon, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.132
    - 15-9-55 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.133
      English; Ansnsol
    - 14-9-55 Assault onT.U. Workers in Ballarrpur Collieries, 1955; 5.746.134
    - 135 16-9-55 Lok Sabha (Question & Answer), 1955; 5.746.135
    - 21-12-55 M.P. Mine Workers' Union Chhindwara-Demand of the Workers, 1955; 5.746.136
      English; Ballarrpur
    - 12-12-55 Pamplet of Madhya Pradesh Khadan mazdoor Sangh - (Aam Hadtaal Suru), 1955; 5.746.137
    - 21-12-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.138
      Hindi; Chhindwara
    - 21-12-55 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1955; 5.746.139
    - 27-12-55 Letter to General secretary, Singareni Collieries Company Ltd., 1955; 5.746.140
  - AITUC Center
    Press clipping related to the strike at FIASCO in Trade Union Record; Press clippings, proceedongs and documents related to the 17th session of Indian Labour Conference of Madras 1959; Report and Memorandum on the service conditions of domestic servants, industrial relations and government of labour policy at the 17th Indian Labour Conference. Papers of United Iron and Steel workers' union.
    - 20-7-59 Trade Union Record - Workers Support Kerala Govt., 1959; 5.49.1
    - 13-7-59 Essential reading for Trade Unionists, Letter To Shri S.A.Dange, M.P., 1959; 5.49.2
    - 20-5-59 Memorandum on Industrial Relations, 1959; 5.49.3
    - Draft Report to the Industrial Relations, 17th I.L.C., 1959; 5.49.4
    - 11-7-59 Press Communique, 1959; 5.49.5
    - 30-7-59 Recourse to Mediation & Arbitration for Settling Industrial Disputes, 1959; 5.49.6
    - 26-7-59 Letter to Shri Gulzari Lal Nanda, Labour minister, 1959; 5.49.7
    - 1-7-59 ILC 17th Session, Madras, 1959; 5.49.8
    - 27 to 29-7-59 ILC 17th Session, Report of the Committee on Service conditions of Domestic Servants, 1959; 5.49.9
    - 17th ILC, 1959; 5.49.10
    - 27 to 29-7-59 Conclusions of the Sittings Held on the 27th July, 1959, 5.49.11
    - 27 to 29-7-59 participation by Observers, 1959; 5.49.12
    - 9-7-59 All Delegates & Advisers, 1959; 5.49.13
    - 1-5-59 Industrial Relations Memorandum, Along with all Annexture, 1959; 5.49.14
    - 1-7-59 Supplementary Note on Iteam No. 3 - Service Conditions of Domestic Servants, 1959; 5.49.15
    - 22-6-59 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1959; 5.49.16
    - 24-6-59 Letter to Shri Mirajkar, President AITUC, 1959; 5.49.17
    - 29-5-59 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1959; 5.49.18
      English; Culcutta
    - Comments Prepared by Dr. Ranen Sen & T.N. Siddhanta, 1959; 5.49.19
    - 29-5-59 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC And Memorundum on Industrial Relasions, 1959; 5.49.20
      English; Punjab & Himachal Pradesh
    - 4-6-59 Notes on the Ministry of Labour's Pamphlet on Industrial Relation, 1959; 5.49.21
    - 26-5-59 Mill Kaamdar Union, Letter to AITUC, 1959; 5.49.22
      English; Bhavnagar, Gujart
    - 28-5-59 Letter and Description to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1959; 5.49.23
      English; Kulti
    - 20-6-59 Letter to The General Secretary, Punjab & Himachal AITUC, 1959; 5.49.24
      English; Amritsar
    - 20-7-59 Letter to Com. Dange, M.P.-Jamshedpur Mazdoor Union, 1959; 5.49.25
      English; Jamshedpur
    - 24-7-59 Letter to Com. Sunderam, 1959; 5.49.26
    - 1-7-59 ILC 17th Session, 1959; 5.49.27
    - 8-4-59 The Indian Trade Unions (Madhya Pradesh Amendment) Bill, 1959, 5.49.28
    - Machinery for Collective Bargaining and the Settlement of Industrial Disputes, 1959; 5.49.29
    - Views of AITUC On Government Labour Policy at 17th ILC, Madras, 1959; 5.49.30
    - 26-7-59 Letter to Shri P.M. Menon I.C.S. Secretary Govt. of India, Labour Depart., 1959; 5.49.31
    - 26-7-59 AITUC Views of AITUC on Goverment Labour Policy at 17th I.L.C., 1959; 5.49.32
  - Dalmianagar Struggle
    Correspondence between the AITUC Bihar state committee and the AITUC General Secretary, K.G. Shrivastava; Documents related to the strike of workers' in Dalmianagar; Report on the work of AITUC Bihar State Committee.
    - 4-12-57 Letter to Com. K.G.Srivastava, 1957; 5.47.1
      English; Patna
    - 8-11-57 Letter to Dear Com. Ratan Roy, 1957; 5.47.2
    - 5-11-57 Letter to Com. K.G.Srivastava, 1957; 5.47.3
    - 10-10-57 Letter to Com. K.G.Srivastava, 1957; 5.47.4
    - 4-10-57 Rohts Industries Limited, Notice, 1957; 5.47.5
      English; Dalmianagar
    - 2-10-57 Memorandum of Agreement, 1957; 5.47.6
    - 9-10-57 Letter to Dear Com. Ratan Roy, 1957; 5.47.7
    - 7-10-57 Letter to The Secretary, Bihar Trade Union Congress, 1957; 5.47.8
    - 26-9-57 Com. Ratan Roy, Bihar Provicial Trade Union Congress, 1957; 5.47.9
    - 17-9-57 Letter to The Secretary, Samyukta Sangharsha samiti, 1957; 5.47.10
    - 24-9-57 Dear Com. Ratan Roy, 1957; 5.47.11
    - 23-9-57 Letter to Com. K.G.Srivastava, 1957; 5.47.12
    - 23-9-57 Dear Com. Ratan Roy, 1957; 5.47.13
    - 20-9-57 Letter to Com. K.G.Srivastava, 1957; 5.47.14
    - 24-8-57 Letter to Com. K.G.Srivastava, 1957; 5.47.15
    - 19-6-57 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1957; 5.47.16
    - Moviment about Increase in Wages Bons and Dearness Allowance & Other Desciptions, 1957; 5.47.17
    - General Review of the Labour Developments, 1957; 5.47.18
  - 3rd International Trades Conference of Metal and Engineering Industries, Prague
    Circulars and appeals from AITUC related to the 3rd international trade union conference of Metal and Engineering Industries in Prague.
    - 16-7-58 Letter from Com. K.G.Srivastava, Secretary, 1958; 5.1019.1
    - 19-2-58 Trade Circular No. 1/58, 1958; 5.1019.2
  - Messages
    Note on the objectives of the All India Convention of States' services at Hyderabad; Invitation and documents, related to the annual conferences and conventions of various workers' unions like: Bombay state pharmaceutical employees' convention, N.F. Railway mazdoor union, Food Employees' Association, Tripura government employees' association, All Utkal students' federation, Palaghat District P.W.D workers' union, Garden reach workshop mazdoor & staff union, Delhi youth federation, Mysore state silk workers' union and Mahashtra state hotel kamgar parishad and similar other unions and association.
    - 6-12-59 Letter to Shri S.A.Dange, M.P., 1959; 5.1274.1
    - Brief note on the Objectives of the All Indian Convention of States, 1959; 5.1274.2
    - 25-12-59 Letter to Shri S.A.Dange M.P.& 2-1-60 Reply to G.Ramachandra Rao, Chairman Reception Committee, 1959; 5.1274.3
    - 23-1-60 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC & 30-1-60 Reply to RC Committee of Bombay State Pharmaceutical Employees Convention, 1960; 5.1274.4
    - 14-1-60 Invitation to S.A.Dange for Annual Conference & Reply to Shri R.K.Sen, N.F.Railways Mazdoor Union, 1960; 5.1274.5
      English; Katihar
    - 26-2-60 Invitation to Indian Coffee House Workers, And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.6
    - 26-2-60 Telegrams: Bankfag, National & Grindlays Bank Employees Union, And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.7
    - 27-2-60 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.8
    - 2-3-60 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.9
      English; Agartala
    - 12-3-60 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.10
    - 5-3-60 Letter to Com. S.A.Dange, President AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.11
      English; Bhadrak
    - 1-3-60 Letter to Com. K.G.Srivastava, Secretary AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.12
    - 18-4-60 Invitation for 5th Annual General Meeting to the Mr. K.G.Srivastava Secretary, AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.13
      English; Gorakhpur
    - 15-4-60 Letter of Janasakti News Paper to Com. S.A.Dange, President AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.14
    - 19-4-60 Letter by Thozhilarasu Journal of SRL Union to Secretary, AITUC And reply from his side, 1960; 5.1274.15
    - 12-5-60 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1960; 5.1274.16